<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Carlos Hinojosa</title>
    <link>http://carloshinojosa.me/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Carlos Hinojosa</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; All right reserved by Carlos Hinojosa, {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://carloshinojosa.me/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Smartphone-based application for agricultural remote technical assistance in Colombia</title>
      <link>http://carloshinojosa.me/project/agrotic-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://carloshinojosa.me/project/agrotic-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) has defined that agriculture is the main source of food supply given the high demand related to the population growth. Therefore, the FAO has also defined the trend to increase agricultural productivity based on the use of technology, information, and com- munication (ICT) tools. Nowadays, recent ICT tools like smartphones, cloud computing, Internet of Things (IoT), and big data support the implementation of precision agriculture to improve crops and their management. Colombia is an abundant country with suitable soils for the cultivation of diverse types of crops. However, the unknown ICT advantages for the farmers and the user rejection to adopt new technology difficult ICT implementation in the Colombian agriculture. On the other hand, the use of smartphones in various industrial applications has brought several advantages, due to their versatility, low-cost, and ease of use. Therefore, smart- phones can be used to address agriculture issues with a promissory implementation. In this sense, this work presents a smartphone application, called AgroTIC, for implementing ICT tools in the traditional work of the Colombian agricultural sector in order to support the productivity of Colombian farmers. AgroTIC takes advantage of smartphone sensors and several ICT tools. Specifically, AgroTIC is composed of four main modules: I) Communication module, II) Image processing and estimation of visible vegetation indices module, III) Production module, and IV) Marketing module. The first allows communication between farmer-to-farmer, and farmers-to-specialists/agronomist for technical assistance remote. The second module is a tool that provides an RGB analysis based on the estimation of two visible vegetation indices to help agronomist in diagnosis. The third module allows farmers to enter information related to their crops to estimate volumes of production and prepare the information for the marketing process. In the fourth module, the farmers can offer their products and establish a direct contact with different potential buyers. AgroTIC has been developed for a community of farmers who grow citrus fruits (orange, tangerine, and Tahiti lime) in the municipality of Simacota, Santander, Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Model-View-ViewModel architectural pattern of the AgroTIC App&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./model.png&#34; alt=&#34;reviews&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.hdsp.agrotic&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./getit2.png&#34; alt=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to depth conversion and seismic interval velocity estimation</title>
      <link>http://carloshinojosa.me/project/seismic-time-to-depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://carloshinojosa.me/project/seismic-time-to-depth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time-domain seismic imaging, also known as time migration, is a fast and robust process for areas with mild lateral
velocity variation. Even so, structural problems by mild lateral velocity variation can appear under this approach.
An alternative known as depth migration manages to mitigate this problem in areas with lateral velocity variation.
Therefore, time-to-depth conversion techniques have been employed to obtain seismic interval velocity. In detail,
these techniques consist of solving a system of partial differential equations ill-posed with missing boundary
conditions, which could lead to stability issues. Thus, an alternative two-step approach, solution of a system of
partial differential equations, and interval velocity estimation from an optimization problem were proposed to
take into account lateral velocity variations for the 2D case. However, the formulation of an optimization problem for
the 3D case is not direct, and it is crucial for the seismic analysis in the interior of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we develop optimization problems to estimate the seismic interval velocity from Dix velocity on 2D
and 3D data using image ray theory. Furthermore, we develop different modules for the DecisionSpace Geoscience software
to implement the designed algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
